Good morning, everybody.
Who would like an authentic
New York bagel, hmm?
Stanley?
Thank you.
Oh, no, no, no. l got
a pumpernickel just
for you.
Wow, H&H.
You went all the way
to New York City to
get us bagels?
Why? ls there a place
closer that sells them?
This is really nice, Dwight.
Thanks.
Oh, don't mention it.
You owe me one.
You all owe me one.
Good morning, Michael.
Morning, Dwight.
Hungry?
Actually, l had two
fish stick sandwiches.
My girlfriend
didn't want hers,
because l guess l'm the
only aphrodisiac she needs.
Fish sticks are
not an aphrodisiac.
Yeah.
You're thinking of deer penis.
lt worked.
Regardless, that was over
two hours ago,
and it is now
a scientific fact
that you are hungry.
Bagel?
l don't mind if l do.
Okay, l brought cheese, too.
l'm taking one
for my lady friend.
Excellent.
Brain food.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
You owe me.
Can't a guy just buy
some bagels for his friends,
so they'll owe him
a favor which he can use
to get someone fired
who stole a co-manager
position from him anymore?
Jeez, when did everyone
get so cynical?
Pam, would you
care for a bagel?
Oh, no, thank you.
Oh, that's right,
you're a woman and you need
to refuse food the first time.
l'll try again.
Please, Pam, reconsider
and have a bagel.
l have an early lunch.
PAM: MichaeI's
been trying to get
Jim and me to hang out
ever since he started
dating my mom.
l don't know.
l really hoped this
thing would just die out,
but today he's planning
a birthday lunch for
my mom.
And we have to go.
No way out.
These are amazing.
You took all these?
l've always
found beauty in
uncommon places.
Homeless people, graffiti.
Photography lets
me capture all that.
Have you ever been
photographed before?
Oh, just by,
like, friends.
Well, here's what l've
been doing around here.
lt's for a series on
exposure in the workplace.
Pammy?
Hey!
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Girls, there they are.
Birthday lunch.
There's no
better medicine
than birthday lunch.
lt'll cure all of your,
"Gee, l don't know
if Michael should be
dating my mother."
And fixes all
occurrences of,
"l don't really
see them together."
So, open wide, Pam,
and take
a big old spoonful of
birthday lunch medicine.
Take with food.
Pam, aren't you
going to introduce us
to Michael's girlfriend?
l think
you guys all remember
my mom from the wedding.
Yeah, l think
everyone's met Helene.
Hi.
MlCHAEL: Shall we?
Wait a minute,
is that another
birthday present for me?
'Cause you already
gave me a necklace.
Oh, my God, l love it.
Tell her how
you gave it to me.
No, that wouldn't be. . .
He put it around my neck
while l was still asleep
this morning.
Nice way to wake up.
MlCHAEL: Yeah.
The rest of the story
has been censored
due to inappropriocity.
Because of sex?
Kevin !
Hey, please, Kevin.
You're fired.
Sorry, sorry, work with
a bunch of idiots.
Shall we go?
HELENE: Yes, let's go.
Oh, wait.
Swartz Lumber's on
the phone for you, Pam.
And they say it's urgent.
Oh, you guys,
just one second.
Oh, my gosh.
Are you serious?
Shipping emergency.
l don't think
l can go to lunch.
Oh, man, that's crazy.
Right as we were on
our way out, too.
l know. lsn't that
always how it goes?
Rarely, if ever.
Let me
give it a whirl,
l'll talk to them.
l will handle it.
That's okay.
l feel like it's. . .
lt's my pleasure.
Hello? Well, that's great.
Turns out,
the paper was
there all along.
Oh, thank God.
Something's up. That paper
was never supposed to arrive.
So, Pammy, are you
still liking sales?
Yeah, it's exciting.
You know, Michael
and l were talking,
and maybe, if you
put in a little more
face-to-face
time with your clients,
you could improve your sales.
Pam's sales
are fine, actually.
Just want you
to succeed, Pammy.
You know what, we shouldn't
even be talking about
business today.
Thank you.
Today's about family.
Why did
l get in the car?
l could've struggled.
l have
a whistle in my purse,
l didn't even blow it.
Oh, Dwight, l have
a little surprise
for you.
Let me guess,
you ate the bagel
l gave you and loved it.
Yes.
And l wanted to
return the favor.
l was polishing my loafers
and l happened to look over
and notice
that your briefcase was
a little worse for the wear,
so a little elbow grease,
and she's
polished right up,
back to her former glory.
Well.
Feel it against your cheek.
l will.
You give me a gift,
bam, thank you note.
You invite me somewhere,
pow, RSVP.
You do me a favor,
wham, favor returned.
Do not test my politeness.
Let me get that door
for you. There we go.
Thank you very much,
and l got it for you.
Oh ! Goodness. Thanks.
You know, here's
a healthy fitness tip,
if you clench your
buttocks together
while walking,
you can really take the
pressure off your knees.
ANDY: ls that right?
DWlGHT: Observe.
(BOTH CHUCKLlNG)
Right?
That really works.
Yeah. Feel free to use that.
Anytime, okay.
Hey, hold on a second.
Do not walk around
with your jacket
catawampus.
And that needs to be
straight as an arrow.
Thank you very much.
Oh, boy.
Hey, thank you
very much for that.
You are welcome.
Have a seat. Allow me.
Have a seat yourself.
You know what?
l am going
to preemptively
change the batteries
in your wireless mouse.
Not necessary.
No, no, no!
You didn't have to do that.
Andy is complicating things.
But l'm not worried.
This will only up my game.
Hello. Scott.
Table for four.
Welcome, Scott family.
lt'll be just a moment.
l used
to love coming here.
The chicken parm is good.
Big part of my childhood.
Maybe Michael will start
dating that, too.
What table
should we take?
So many to choose from.
Wow.
Oh, my God.
What? All l see are
boring old tables with
no birthday decorations.
Oh, wait a second,
you mean this one? Wow!
Michael, you did all this?
lt's not about taking credit.
Let's just say we all did it.
Well, thank you,
all of you.
Well, it was actually
me alone, so. . .
Wow, look at this place.
lt really
makes me want to
go to ltaly someday.
Oh, you'll love it.
You can have my guidebooks.
l think
l'm done with those
really long plane rides.
Thank you for. . .
Thanks for
lending me the books.
So, Mom, which birthday
are we celebrating this year?
Sticking with 49.
Forty-nine again?
That's nine years in a row.
This is now our longest
family tradition.
That's funny.
Well, as long as
we're running numbers, Pam,
help me out with this one.
Let's see, honey,
you're six months pregnant,
but you've only been married
for 30 days, so what does
that add up to?
Ooh, burn, burn on you.
And a little bit on me, too.
You're 54 years old.
No, l'm 58.
You're 58 years old?
Uh-huh.
Congratulations.
The only time
you should care
about a woman's age
is if she is
too young for you.
And l am not
robbing the cradle.
lf anything,
l am robbing the grave.
Mom, have you decided
what you want to be called?
l mean, l like Nana,
but l also like the
classic Grandma.
Please be Grandma.
l want you to be Grandma.
Definitely a Grandma.
(EXCLAlMS) Michael.
What do you think? Grandma?
Uh-huh.
Yay! Grandma.
Hey, would you guys
ever do a triathlon,
you think?
Maybe.
Helene?
No. l don't think so.
l am.
l'm definitely
going to do it.
l've already
got the run and
the bike thing down,
just need to learn how
to swim. Come on, you in?
No, no. l think a triathlon
is pretty much something
l can rule out.
l don't know, it just
doesn't interest me.
So, it's a matter of
interest. Good. Okay.
lt's not anything you
would have ever done?
l might have done it
when l was younger,
but now
there are just other
things l'd rather be doing
than running and jumping
and swimming. . .
Well, there's no
jumping in a triathlon.
Oh !
You're thinking
the broad jump.
Would you try bungee jumping?
No.
Snowboarding?
No, no, you want
to go snowboarding?
l might, l might.
Michael, what are
you talking about?
(SlGHS)
Nothing, just life
and doing things
before you die.
l don't know.
Do l really want to
go snowboarding? No.
But l would like to
if l wanted to.
(MlMlCKlNG FANFARE)
(EXCLAlMlNG)
What's going on in here?
Andy bought lunch.
Oh, no, really?
Yep, yep.
Took a page right out of the
old Schrute book of niceness.
There is no book,
there's only a survival guide.
You bought
breakfast for everyone,
so l got
lunch for everyone.
Okay, well, allow me.
You know what?
Gosh, these tacos are
awfully complicated
to make.
l will make
everyone's tacos!
(EXCLAlMlNG)
So we should
get the check.
What about your gift, Michael?
Whoa, no, no, no.
No, it's stupid.
You'd hate it, l hate it.
l'm sure l won't.
Yes, you will.
He locked
himself in his office
all morning working on it.
Give me. Look at
this wrapping paper.
lt's got the word "love"
on it in every language.
l literally. . .
l put no thought
into the wrapping at all.
Might as well
have been toilet paper.
Toilet paper. Let's see.
"A scrapbook of
our first memories,
by Michael Gary Scott,
"for my girlfriend,
Helene, on your birthday."
That's just an
arbitrary title.
Okay, here's a penny.
What's that from?
Penny for your thoughts.
lt was from the
wishing well
at the mall.
You threw it in,
l went back later,
waded in, and l found it.
That's amazing.
lt's not amazing at all.
lt's sort of weird that
l went and did that.
And now your wish
won't come true,
so that blows.
A poem.
Oh, that l plagiarized,
l think.
"l cannot go to school today
said little Peggy Ann McKay"
Shel Silverstein?
Yeah.
"l have the measles
and the mumps
"a gash, a rash,
and purple bumps
"And my teacher's
really mean
"Happy Birthday,
l love you, Helene."
lt's really
nice, Michael.
l think it sucks.
l think
it's wonderful,
absolutely wonderful.
Well, that's
because you and l
have very different tastes,
and you like lame things.
lt's a generational
sort of gap between us.
Oh, God, a scrapbook.
Home run, Michael.
You set the bar so high.
That was a bunt.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Dwight,
l'm going to do this.
Hey, hey, hey, relax.
l got it covered.
No, l insist.
No, no, no, no, no, l insist.
Okay, Dwight,
this is ridiculous.
Don't worry about it,
you can just owe me.
Hey, where'd you go?
Oh, l just went
to the bathroom.
And then you stopped at
the bar on the way back?
Got thirsty.
Okay, weirdo.
Come on, it's time for cake.
Okay.
Honestly, for a long time,
l thought l was going
to grow old with Holly.
And then l met Helene,
and she is great,
and she already knows
and has done everything
that l have
ever wanted to do
and can tell me about it.
But l think l want to
do those things myself.
Cake's really good.
l know.
l love when they use
butter-cream frosting.
Finish your cake, Helene.
l want you to
enjoy that cake
because l have something
terrible l need to tell you.
And l want you
to enjoy your cake
before l tell you this
terrible, terrible thing.
Helene, l think you're
a wonderful person and l. . .
God, l've enjoyed
dating you
and being your
boyfriend so much,
but l have to
consider Pam's feelings
as a friend and a coworker.
l cannot,
in good conscience,
continue to date you,
when l know what
this is doing to her.
Michael. Michael, it's okay.
No, it's not.
l know that it took me
a little while to
come around,
and it's still
a little weird
to get used to,
but you obviously
make my mom very happy.
And that makes me happy.
Wow, that just. . .
You've really grown.
Well. . .
Oh, thank you, Pam.
And l hope you are
as gracious during
this next part.
Helene, once again,
you are a wonderful person,
and you have
lived a great life,
and l envy it,
and l want it someday,
but just in the future.
You need somebody who
understands your references.
Who is Kafka-esque?
l've never. . .
l don't know him.
There's another woman,
and her name is ltaly,
and skydiving,
and bungee jumping.
Okay, so. . .
And l want kids.
And you, unfortunately,
have already completed
that part of your
journey down there.
Michael.
lt's not my decision,
it's Mother Nature.
And Mother has very
strict rules about
fertility.
(STUTTERS) l got it.
l'm 58. What am l
supposed to do now?
Well, hobbies.
Stop.
(GROANS)
What's going on?
Stupid thing wedged up there.
No one in this
office will help me.
Yeah, move it.
What if Dwight dies
and l still owe him
something?
That is a recipe
for a ghost.
Oh, yeah,
you're gonna
owe me big time.
Looks like a little
envelope, there you go.
Yup. Got it.
"To Dwight"?
Starbucks gift card.
Surprise!
lt's from everybody.
$1 5 value.
Damn it!
l am no closer
to taking Jim down.
(EXCLAlMS)
What a waste of a day.
l could've
grown poison mushrooms
that'd be this high by now!
They're mushrooms,
they don't get that high.
Pamela Beesly-Halpert.
What?
May l have
a word with you
in my office, please?
l am working.
Well, this is
a work-related matter.
Really?
Yes.
Join me, please,
won't you?
l'm going to give you
a raise, Pam.
Why?
Because of
all the good
work you've done.
l have
the lowest sales
record of anyone here.
Don't, no.
lt's not about numbers Pam,
it's about attitude.
l have
the worst attitude
of any person here.
Do you want
the raise or what?
Yeah, l'll take it.
Okay, hey. Pam, Pam.
With this raise,
there are strings attached.
And that string is attached
from my heart to your
mean attitude.
You're bribing me?
No, no. No, l am not.
Unless you want me to.
Do you want me to?
Because l will,
l will bribe you.
No, your face is saying
don't, unless l haven't
offered you enough.
Your face isn't changing.
What is it?
Talk to me, face.
Tell me what
Pam's brain is thinking.
Come on,
what do you want?
What do you want?
Do you want
a million dollars?
Do you want to hit me?
Do you
want me to get down
on one knee and beg you?
l want to hit you.
What?
l'll do that.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
What? l don't. . .
Are you kidding?
No, are you kidding?
No, l don't. . .
All right. Come on,
l'll take off my jacket
and tense my stomach
and you just. . .
No, l don't think
l can hit you in
the office.
Okay.
So, we'll do it after work.
Hmm.
ln the parking lot,
in front of everyone.
l'm going to hit you
as hard as l can.
Okay.
See you then.
See you.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
RYAN: Hey.
Hi.
Quick question.
Yeah.
Are you scared?
Never.
About what? A little.
What are you talking about?
We heard about the punch.
What punch?
Pam. She's going
to punch the crap out
of your face after work.
l'm pretty sure we said slap.
No, it's a punch and Pam
has that crazy pregnancy
strength now.
l'm getting concerned
that you don't seem
to understand
what's going to happen.
Do you?
(EXCLAlMS) l'm good.
RYAN:
All right.
See you there.
Hey.
Do you and Pam
ever get frisky?
lnappropriate.
l mean, do you ever
wrestle with each other?
All the time.
Really?
Yeah.
She's strong?
She wants it bad, Michael.
Can you stop this?
l can.
Okay.
And l don't support
her choice to hit you.
l don't, either.
But at the same time,
she goes crazy,
and l do
understand her reasoning.
Mmm-hmm. l know.
l just need some time.
l need some time to
think about it.
You got to do. . .
Give me some time
to make a decision.
How much time do you need?
No more than a week,
maybe two weeks.
Come on, man.
Pam, can l talk
to you for a second?
l heard
about the hit.
Just to be sure,
it's off company
property, right?
Right.
Yeah, okay, l think we
should probably be okay.
Okay.
(WHlSPERS) And the power
comes from the back foot.
So, it's all one motion
through the body.
So, there's. . .
You stay a little
low and there's a twist,
and you keep
your shoulder down.
And you kind of
throw out the arm.
(EXCLAlMS)
Okay, wait,
you're saying it
comes from the foot?
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
Hey, everybody.
He's not in the men's room,
although the seat was warm,
so we may have
just missed him.
My money's on Pam.
lt's not a fight.
What other outcome
could there be?
Michael could win.
How? He can't hit back.
Why can't you just
agree with me sometimes?
Am l scared of getting
hit in the face? No.
Every day, weirdos pay
dominatrixes hundreds
of dollars
for that very privilege.
l'm scared l'm going
to love it. Let's do this.
lt's okay, guys.
l can handle this.
Everybody can go home.
We're here for
the show, Michael.
You're just
a bunch of voyeurs.
Are you eating popcorn?
lt has almost no calories.
You ready?
Yes.
You have to
keep your hands down.
l know.
(EXHALES)
Okay. All right.
Oh, God !
Michael, you have to
keep your hands down.
Put your hands
in your pockets.
Okay!
Pam, Pam.
l'm really sorry.
l'm sorry.
What are you sorry for?
So many things.
l don't know,
it's hard to choose.
How about for dating my mom?
Maybe that's it.
And dumping her
on her birthday?
Yes.
Okay, just don't ever date
a member of my family again.
Okay, l promise.
For the record,
your mom came on to me.
Holy crap!
Are you okay?
No!
You're okay.
Feel better?
No, you were right.
Wait, why are you limping?
l don't know.
Let's get some
raw meat on that face.
l've got a chicken
in the freezer upstairs.
As l watched Pam's big,
strong hand coming
toward my face,
l saw my entire life
flash before my eyes.
And guess what?
l have four kids.
And l have a hover car
and a hover house.
And my wife is a runner,
and it shows.
And Pam and Jim
are my best friends,
and our kids play together.
And l'm happy.
And l am rich
and l never die.
lt doesn't
sound like much,
but it's enough for me.
Good, good, just keep it
on there for another
five minutes.
lt's cold, Dwight.
Let the swelling go down.
Oh, thank you. Thanks.
l owe you one, Dwight.
Fire Jim.
No.
l'm cashing in
the favor, fire him.
What are you talking. . .
Do it.
Promote me.
Tri-managers.
Forget that.
Can l have an office?
No.
You know what, you can
keep your stupid favor.
lt's worthless.
And this is my dinner on
your face, l'm keeping it.
Oh, that feels better.